The only safe place is on the run.
Snowden is a drama, history, crime film directed by Oliver Stone.
CIA employee Edward Snowden leaks thousands of
classified documents to the press.
Edward Snowden, played by Joseph Gordon-Levitt.
Lindsay Mills, played by Shailene Woodley.
Laura Poitras, played by Melissa Leo.
Glenn Greenwald, played by Zachary Quinto.
Ewen MacAskill, played by Tom Wilkinson.
Trevor James, played by Scott Eastwood.
Snowden is a 2016 biographical thriller film directed by Oliver
Stone and written by Stone and Kieran Fitzgerald.
Based on the books The Snowden Files (2014) by Luke Harding and Time of the Octopus (2015) by Anatoly Kucherena, the film stars Joseph Gordon-Levitt as Edward Snowden, a Central
Intelligence Agency (CIA) subcontractor and whistleblower who copied and leaked highly classified information from the National Security Agency (NSA) beginning in 2013.
In addition to Gordon-Levitt, the film features an ensemble cast including Shailene Woodley, Melissa Leo, Zachary Quinto, Tom Wilkinson,
Scott Eastwood, Logan Marshall-Green, Timothy Olyphant, Ben Schnetzer, LaKeith Lee Stanfield, Rhys Ifans and Nicolas Cage.
An international co-production of Germany, France, and the United States,
principal photography began on February 16, 2015, in Munich.
Snowden screened at San Diego Comic-Con on July 21, 2016, before premiering at
the 2016 Toronto International Film Festival on September 9, 2016.
The film was theatrically released in the United States on September 16,
2016, by Open Road Films and on September 22 in Germany.
It received mixed reviews from critics, who praised
Gordon-Levitt's performance but criticized Stone's direction.
It grossed $37.3 million worldwide against its $40 million budget.
The film explores themes of biography, idealism, idealist, national
security agency (nsa), investigative journalism.
The tone is emotional and intense.